# **Bshr Ramadan**

# Computer & Software Engineer

💌 bshr.ramadan.96@gmail.com 📞 +963941405267 👂 Damascus, Syria 🛮 in bshr-ramadan

bshrram

# **PROFILE**

Computer Engineer with 4 years of professional work experience in backend development. Experienced with a wide range of development languages, frameworks and tools, including Node.js, Golang, C++, Rest & Graphql apis, AWS, Monitoring and CI tools, ...etc.

Delivered successful projects and have experience working on large scale projects. Possesses strong problem-solving skills and is able to quickly identify and resolve issues. Excellent collaboration skills, and able to work as part of a team or independently.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Software Engineer** 

Stowk (movecar) ≥

04/2021 - present **US - Remotely** 

- Developing and supporting applications, database integration, and new feature enhancements.
- Collaborated with the remote team of engineers on moving to a new scalable infrastructure, automating deployments and improving performance, reducing costs by around 80% in result.
- Participated effectively in meetings and provide valuable suggestions for technical and business processes.
- Some skills used: Node.js, Golang, AWS, Serverless-Stack(SST), MongoDB, Apollo Graphql-Federation

#### **Backend Developer**

- 05/2022 05/2023 **UAE - Remotely**
- Designed and implemented a SaaS e-commerce service with Golang and No-SQL architecture, providing high performance and low resources usage, and communicating with tens of other existing microservices in the company system through synchronous and asynchronous protocols, which are managed with Kubernetes.
- · Worked with a team of expert coders to write maintainable code and maintain existing software to improve performance and fix bugs, using many technologies like: Golang, Node.js, SQL, NoSQL, Docker, ...
- Followed OWASP practices to improve web applications security.

### **Back-End Developer**

Unifi.Solutions ≥

- Canada Remotely
- · Handled and implemented the back logic of much software including a chat application, an IOT platform with thousands of devices, an app organizing Islamic procedures in Canada, and home automation platform.
- Worked in contributed with a team and as a leader of a sub-team.
- Some skills used: Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Socket.io

### **Developer**

*iEducate* Worked with team on creating a new iEducate app, admin dashboard and their

backend, using: Node.js - React - ReactNative - Loopback.js - MongoDB

### Web developer, Contracts

- The first real-world experience was in 2017 by participating in developing SuperMarkBot Ø with a team of university colleagues, using Node.js - MongoDB -Microsoft bot framework.
- Then worked with BrainSocket Ø Team on a REST API for a website, using node.js - Loopback.js - mongoDB.

11/2020 - 04/2021

10/2019 - 12/2020 Damasucs, Syria

04/2017 - 03/2019

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Computer Engineering**

Damascus University *⊘* 

11/2014 - 10/2020 Damascus, Syria

- My graduation project ∂ accomplishes first place in Tamayuz Competition all over 160 projects with 300 participants participated from different cities in Syria.
- participated in the Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC) multiple times, refining my skills and knowledge in programming and problem-solving.

# **SKILLS**

### **Programming Languages**

Golang, Javascript, Typescript, C++, Python

#### **Web Technologies**

Node.js, Go, Rest-Apis, Graphql-Apis, MongoDB, SQL, React.js

### **Cloud Technologies**

AWS Serverless Lambda functions, AWS CDK(infrastructure as code), Containerizing with Docker, Orchestration with Kubernetes, Github-Actions as CI

# **LANGUAGES**

**Arabic English** Native Intermediate

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# Kids and Adolescents Programming Marathon - KPM ⊘

**Programming Coach** 

Teaching computer science to kids and adolescents in a way that matches their age and abilities, helping them meet their growing needs in programming and information.

RBCs Team 🔗 11/2014 - 04/2018 Social Manager, Copywriter

Provide scientific support and assistance to increase the practical skills for university's students.

05/2019 - 01/2020 Damascus, Syria

Damascus, Syria